Domacor Mentee

781-228-9175 · mentee.domacor@gmail.com · Boston, MA · https://github.com/dommenteehttps://www.linkedin.com/in/domacor-mentee-7aa486126/">https://github.com/dommenteehttps://www.linkedin.com/in/domacor-mentee-7aa486126/

Versatile software engineer and agile project manager with experience building full-CRUD applications using PERN and MERN stacks. Team-oriented creative with insight on planning, collaborating, and iteration. Avid problem solver and designer that holds structure, functionalities and design of user interfaces and experience at equal priority. Associate in computer science and General assembly alum that integrates new processes, concepts and methodologies into a substantial skillset.

Skills: JavaScript, React.js, Vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, Python 3.7, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Less, Bootstrap, SQLite, MySQL, Heroku, PostgreSQL, Postman, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Django, Figma, Typescript, Git, GitHub, Java, Photoshop, Django, Responsive design, web development

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS Sur+Gical

Sept 2021 - Present December 2021

- Concept: A tool that brings the average cost and heal time of any medical procedure to the user. The goal was to make the data visually pleasing while suggesting medical institutions to the user.
- Used PERN stack (Postgres, Express, React, node) to build a full stack application in 2 days, with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Utilized TypeScript to organize data types which led to less errors and faster development.

<u>Travel Stories</u> November 2021

- Concept: An application that lists different activities based on a searched destination.
- Full stack MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) application with full CRUD operation.
- Collaborated on a team of two where I was responsible for the GitHub collaborative environment, REST API setup, ReactJS development and deployment.

United-We Art October 2021

- Concept: An app where artists create, share a professional portfolio, and can connect and collaborate with other artists.
- Utilized Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express and EJS to build a full stack application with CRUD capabilities.
- Leveraged Node packages for user authentication, account creation and user cookie sessions for login/logout.

Professional Experience

General Assembly — Software Engineering Student — Boston, MA

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

 Completed a three-month,420+ hours full-stack program that builds experience with the latest frontand back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies of software engineering, web development, responsive design including: JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML5, CSS, SASS, LESS, jQuery, PostgreSQL, TypeScript, Figma, MongoDB, Django, NodeJS, Git, GitHub, and Agile/Scrum.

JetBlue Airways — *Ground Operations Lead* – Boston, MA

Aug 2013 - Present

- Leading a team and communicating with various departments to ensure proficiency and operational metrics are met.
- Responsible for recording and reporting aircraft load plans, aircraft servicing of lavatory and water, and required maintenance.
- Keeping safety as priority by leading my team to follow guidelines, doing security and safety walk rounds to ensure aircrafts are safe to operate.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

December 2021

Software Engineering Immersive

Massasoit Community College

January 2021

Associates in Arts - Computer Science